Having problems logging into Grex?

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Many times, problems with logging in can be as simple as an incorrectly typed password or login, but sometimes, the reasons can be more subtle. The following is a list of messages you might see; follow the link to learn more details about each message.

Common login errors

No such loginid
This loginid disabled
Incorrect password
Invalid login time
Sorry, root logins not allowed on this line
Access Denied
Excessive login failures for this loginid

No such loginid

The login name that you entered does not exist on Grex. Check first to be sure you spelled it correctly. Note that your login name must be typed in all lower-case letters and numbers.

If you haven't logged into your Grex account recently, it is possible that it has been deleted. It is our practice to remove accounts that have not been used for 90 days or more. With more than 200 new accounts created on Grex every day, we must delete unused accounts to free up resources. Even with this policy, we still have over 27,000 active accounts on Grex. You can use the form at the bottom of this page to check if an account exists.

If your account was reaped (deleted), feel free to recreate the account by logging in as newuser. This link requires that your browser can start an SSH client. An alternative is to use the web-based MindTerm Java SSH client. We are sorry for the inconvenience. We hope we can welcome you back to Grex.

This loginid disabled

If you see this, first check to see that you typed your loginid in correctly. If your account was locked, you will see this message. Generally, this means we saw your account being used for an inappropriate purpose. If you want your account unlocked, you will need to send mail to help@grex.org that says what you did wrong, why what you did was wrong, and that you promise not to do the bad thing again.

Incorrect password

The password you supplied was not correct. You may have mistyped or misremembered your password. Case matters, so check to be sure that you don't have caps-lock turned on.

If you have not used your account recently, it may have been reaped, and the login name may have been claimed by another person. Inactive accounts are reaped (deleted) after 90 days, after which it is possible for another person to reuse the same login name. You can use the form at the bottom of this page to check the owner of the account and see if it is you. If your account was reaped, feel free to log in as newuser and create a new account. This link requires that your browser can start an SSH client. An alternative is to use the web-based MindTerm Java SSH client.

If you have used your account recently, and really cannot remember the password, please send E-mail to help@grex.org and indicate that you have forgotten your password. If you have previously left sufficient identifying information with your account that we can verify that you are really you, we will reset your password. Please do NOT tell us what you think your password is, or was. We do not keep a password history, and obviously your present password is wrong.

In fact, please don't ever tell anyone your password, not even your best friend or lover. Also, for your protection, don't use your grex password on any other system.

Invalid login time

This message should not occur. Send E-mail to help@grex.org if you believe you have seen this error message. Please include the date and time you tried it.

Sorry, root logins not allowed on this line

Root access is used by certain grex staff members for system maintenance purposes, but only by using sudo after logging in normally.

Access Denied

This message may occur if your IP address (likely provided by your Internet Service Provider dynamically) is on a block or black list. Grex subscribes to several IP block or black lists to help prevent people from damaging Grex. Ideally your ISP would do something about this because they assigned you an IP address that is known around the Internet as engaging in illegal or unethical activities. Ask them to give you a different IP address would be one solution. Please send E-mail to help@grex.org if you see this message and Grex staff can determine if your IP address is being blocked for this reason.

Excessive login failures for this loginid

This message should not normally occur. If it occurs, it indicates that a person was trying to break into your account, and failed. Please send E-mail to help@grex.org if you see this message.

Check Information about a Grex Account

To check if an account exists, or if it is your account, enter the login name in the box below and submit it. This will display public information about the account if it exists.

login:

Contact Information

Cyberspace Communications, Inc.
P.O. Box 4432
Ann Arbor, MI 48106-4432
USA

Grex FAQ - Send email to help@grex.org

$Id: badlogin.xhtml 1540 2016-06-11 16:25:41Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.

Conferencing on Grex

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Conferences (BBS, forums) can be accessed in 3 ways:

via the Unix shell on the Grex Unix server, by typing: bbs or ft at the shell prompt. To connect to the Grex server you need to SSH or ssh with a browser. Note: this link will only work if your browser has been configured to start a SSH client. If it doesn't work, you may need to change your browser's preferences, or in some cases, download an SSH client application program.
via a web browser
by downloading Fronttalk (ft) to your computer and running it; this requires some form of Perl to be installed (ActivePerl, on Windows).

The conferences are the heart of Grex. Since its inception in 1991, Grex has provided conferencing as a way for people to get to know each other, exchange ideas and form virtual communities based on shared interests.

There are now a large number of conferences on Grex, covering a wide range of topics. A number of these are highlighted on our front page, but here is a complete list.

These conferences were at first only accessible by dialing into Grex and running Picospan - a software developed in 1983 by a Grex staff member (Marcus D. Watts).

Within a few years, Grex added an internet connection which permitted users from all over the world to participate in these conferences. We now have users from many countries, with many different points of view, and many interesting stories to tell.

In 1996, when the web became more popular, two other Grex Staff members developed the Backtalk conferencing system. This further simplifies the process of participating in these conferences by making access possible to all of Grex's conferences directly from a web browser, with no need to connect by SSH. Backtalk is fully compatible with Picospan, and they share the same conference database on Grex, so it really makes no difference which one you use.

Eventually, the two Grex Staff members developed the Fronttalk client to the Backtalk conferencing system. This further simplifies the process of participating in these conferences by making access possible to all of Grex's conferences directly from any machine, with no need to connect by SSH, just by installing fronttalk. Fronttalk looks like Picospan, when running.

Today, PicoSpan has been retired and replaced by FrontTalk.

OK, then. Let's go to the conferences

See more about Grex's history.

$Id: confs.xhtml 1422 2014-03-23 00:56:43Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.

E-mail on Grex

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Grex provides free email accounts to anyone who wants one. This service is made available in the spirit of improving people's ability to communicate with each other.

Once you have a validated Grex account, your E-mail address is either accountname@grex.org or accountname@cyberspace.org. You may use whichever address you prefer.

Grex offers POP3 and IMAP E-mail connections for use with an E-mail client supporting either of those protocols. Grex requires a secure connection for this to work. As an example, here's how to connect with IMAP from your local computer running an e-mail client, such as Thunderbird: Tell your client to use grex.org or cyberspace.org as the e-mail server. Connect on port 143 with STARTTLS (SSL/TLS and port 993 will also work) for security, and use your Grex username and password to authenticate.

Grex does not support Web-based mail right now.

You may also use a text terminal to read or send E-mail from Grex. To do this, you can SSH to Grex. Note: this link will only work if your browser supports the SSH protocol or if your browser has been configured to start an SSH client. If it doesn't work, you may need to change your browser's preferences, or in some cases, download an SSH client application program.

Once you have connected by SSH and logged in, you can use any of the mail clients available on Grex. Currently, we support alpine, elm, mutt, nmh, and mail. We will consider installing other programs, upon request.

This process of connecting to read mail can be greatly simplified and made more secure by the use of public-key cryptography with SSH. SSH is a secure means of communication because it uses data encryption.

E-mail is a very popular service, and so it is necessary for Grex to establish an acceptable use policy for E-mail. Ideally, we would not like to have many rules, but we have found that we need to have a few in order to assure the smooth flow of mail to so many users.

Acceptable Use Policy for Grex E-mail

Do not send unsolicited or unwanted mail. This includes mail intended to harass other users.
Do not send or encourage anyone to send you messages longer than 100k. Usually mail that large contains an attached file, often a binary file. If you must send or receive attachments, make sure that they are small and infrequent.
If you choose to have your mail forwarded to another machine, you must limit the forwarding to a single site. Do not use the forwarding service to setup a mailing list.
If forwarding mail, do not forward any bulk mail. Bulk mail is mail that comes from a list server. Instead, you must unsubscribe your Grex account from the list server, and subscribe to the list from where you wish to receive your mail.
Read your mail regularly. If you are receiving mail from a list server that you do not have time to read, unsubscribe from the mailing list. If your mailbox gets too big, your mail will bounce.

Users interested in using other mail clients should send email to help@grex.org.

$Id: email.xhtml 1407 2014-03-22 22:21:57Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.

How Grex was Started

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Grex was created by users from the M-Net system in Ann Arbor, MI, who had grown discontent with how that system was run. The text below was "lifted" from the Coop Conference in about 1994 from an item about the history of Grex; a far more complete history can be found on Dr. Jan Wolter's personal site.

#3 of 15: by STeve Andre' (steve) on Fri, Dec 17, 1993 (10:41): Actually Tim, that isn't right. Marcus and I first starting talking about "another" conferencing system in town as early as 1987. That doesn't include other folks conversations either. So there really was thought of something other than M-Net for quite a few years before Grex happened. During the founder's meetings, it did appear that M-Net really was going to die. To state that it was kite's fault is too simple. There were a lot of factors in there, all mixed together.

#4 of 15: by Rane Curl (rcurl) on Fri, Dec 17, 1993 (22:26): Tell us the story, Steve.

#5 of 15: by TS Taylor (tsty) on Sun, Dec 19, 1993 (01:49): OH, boy .... it's almost a PhD dissertation in and of itself, which some socal "scientist" might consider ......... From the outsider's perspective, which is all I have even having listened to several varities of POV, xD there really is +no+ simple answer/story. Quoting STeve, "there wer a lot of factors in there, all mixed together," and that's almost an understatement.

#6 of 15: by Valerie Mates (popcorn) on Sun, Dec 19, 1993 (11:05): The short version is: Back when M-Net was the only conferencing system in town it was owned first by Mike Myers, then by Dave Parks. Dave had a tendency to expect the users to spontaneously send in money to keep the system running, without being asked, and he used to get upset when the bills came in and the user donations didn't. He would often decide to shut the system down, forever, on 3 hours notice or less. One angel or another always came through and saved the system from financial ruin, but the angels all wore out after rescuing the system a couple of times. Meanwhile, the threatened shutdowns left people leery of sending in $150 for a year's patronship on a system that might be shut down tomorrow. Dave Parks is a wonderful, kind, caring person (I like him a lot as a person) but his policies as a system owner tended to come across as autocratic and abrupt.

A group of a dozen users met weekly for six months, planning a new system, owned by its members and founded on slow, group decisionmaking. We ate lots of pot luck dinners together and planned lots of idealistic ideas about how Grex would work. We located the hardware and a space to put it in. We incorporated as Cyberspace Communications, Inc., and we picked out the name Grex. We hashed out plans for how the users would control the system, placing incredible care in setting up a mechanism which users could use to change any rules of the system.

I remember vividly the founders meeting on the night when the US first bombed Iraq. It was hard to concentrate on issues as mundane as a computer system.

The twelve founders were: Denise Anderson (denise), Steve Andre (steve), Misti Anslin (mta), Tom Doehne (arthur), Brian Dunkle (bad), Valerie Mates (popcorn), Marc Unangst (mju) (our token minor), John Remmers (remmers), Mary Remmers (chelsea) (or was she Mary Valdivia at the time?), Fred Sleator, Mike Smerza (morel), and Marcus Watts (mdw). Glenda Andre was present at lots of meetings, too.

We worried that users wouldn't feel a sense of ownership in the system, so we held a big "Friends of Grex ('FOG')" meeting at Island Park shortly before the system opened. Quite a number of M-Net users showed up. There were a couple of issues the founders hadn't come to any decision on, so we worked these issues out at the FOG meeting to practice group decision making face to face. The first fairwitnesses of the Agora conference were chosen: Katie Geddes and Larry Kestenbaum.

That was two and a half years ago. It's been about 3 years since the first founders meetings. Grex has grown past my wildest dreams. I'd figured it would remain no bigger than an expensive playground for the founders. Instead, today there are hundreds of users and a thriving system. I am pleased.

#7 of 15: by Dan Romanchik (danr) on Sun, Dec 19, 1993 (11:09): Here's my take on the Dave Parks controversy.

M-Net, like Grex, is fairly expensive to operate. M-Net is undoubtedly more expensive because they have more phone lines. These bills were Parks' responsibility because he owned m-net lock, stock, and barrel.

At one point, the bills got to be too much for him, and he started turning up the heat in getting people to donate. (Parks and his predecessor, Mike Myers, had always accepted donaations, but prior to this point were always pretty laid back about soliciting.) Every other day it seemed like he would threaten to pull the plug unless users started sending donations. He actually took the system off-line a couple of times as I remember.

Parks got himself into a real Catch 22 with this strategy. He wanted people to donate, and yet kept threatening to cease operation. Well, it doesn't take a rocket scientist to figure out that this was not the smartest approach to easing his financial crisis. I, for one, was not going to send him a cent until I could be guaranteed that the system was going to be around for a while.

Parks' other problem was that he wanted to have his cake and eat it, too. He wanted people to send him money, yet he did not want to release any financial information about the system, nor did he want to give people any control over the system. It was his fiefdom, and he wanted to keep it that way, AND he wanted the users to pay for it.

These were the conditions that led to the formation of Grex and the M-Net/Arbornet groups. The users that formed the M=Net/Arbornet group purchased the system from Dave and moved it to the space where we plan to move soon. That's about all I can say about M-net/Arbornet; I never got involved with their politics.

#8 of 15: by Dan Romanchik (danr) on Sun, Dec 19, 1993 (11:11): Valerie's response slipped in. Good thing we didn't contradict one another. :)

#9 of 15: by Josh Grosse (jdg) on Sun, Dec 19, 1993 (13:50): You may need a little more information on the financial arrangement between Parks and Myers. It helps explain Dave's actions a little bit more -- at the least, it gives a motive. Dave "rescued" M-Net from Mike by paying what everyone (else) thought was a price well above market value for the equipment and software. Dave justified this to himself by thinking he'd bought a lot of goodwill and market value. This turned out not to be the case. The goodwill lasted until the first threatened shutdown, and the market value lasted only until the market found other avenues. As we all know, personality conflicts exacerbated things, too.

#10 of 15: by Patricia Snyder-Rayl (pegasus) on Sun, Dec 19, 1993 (20:27): The concept was good... a local pay BBS ... but it would seem the execution of the concept was a little less than desirable. Well, I'm just as glad to have Grex here, no matter the circumstances!

#11 of 15: by John H. Remmers (remmers) on Sun, Dec 19, 1993 (22:02): It's interesting that once Grex went on-line to the public, it was not very much longer that M-Net remained a single-owner system. I suspect that the existence of Grex was a significant factor in Dave's decision to sell M-Net for a price that someone was willing to pay. Ironically, it was about two or three months after Grex started up that M-Net was purchased by a group and re-organized as a non-profit corporation along lines similar to Grex.

$Id: history.xhtml 1433 2014-03-23 01:23:56Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.

Frequently Asked Questions about
Becoming a Member of "Grex

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Do I have to become a member in order to use Grex?
What benefits do I get for becoming a member of Grex?
Is there a form I need to fill out to become a member?
Can I pay my dues with my credit card?
Does it cost Grex money if I pay by credit card?
Are my membership dues tax-deductible?
If I become a member, can I run an IRC bot such as Eggdrop on Grex?
If I become a member, can I put pictures on my web site?
Do I have to identify myself in order to become a member of Grex?
Why?
What forms of ID are acceptable?
I'm paying for my membership with Paypal. Do I still need to send ID?
But the whole point of using Paypal was I didn't want to send mail! Is there any other way I can send the treasurer my ID?
Who will get to see my ID?
I live outside the US and don't have access to a US checking account. Can I become a member?
Can my organization become a member of Grex?
What kind of ID is needed for an institutional membership?
How soon after I send in my payment will I be made a member?
Is there anything that might prevent me from being added right away?
How will I know when my membership is activated?
Can I donate old computer equipment in lieu of paying dues?
I am an experienced UNIX user. Can I do system administration work in lieu of paying dues?
What can I do if I don't like these policies?

Do I have to become a member in order to use Grex?

No. Anyone is welcome to join the Grex community, free of charge. But about 75% of Grex's operating expenses are paid with membership dues, so if you find Grex to be valuable, we hope you will consider becoming a member.

What benefits do I get for becoming a member of Grex?

First of all, Grex is not an ISP, and so does not sell Internet access. Membership dues are donations to help support Grex, not payments for services rendered. Part of Grex's charitable mission is to provide limited connectivity for people who otherwise couldn't afford it, so we have tried to keep the gap between what members can do and what everyone else can do small.

So the real answer is, the main thing you get is the satisfaction of supporting a great community, and a great community resource. You also get the ability to vote in Grex elections, so you can help decide Grex's future. (You have to pay for three months or more before you can vote.)

There are also a few technical advantages to being a member. Certain of our Internet resources are too limited to grant to everyone who has an account on Grex, so they are reserved for members only. Specifically, non-members are forbidden internet access except via these protocols: finger, gopher, talk, and http. All other internet protocols (such as SSH, FTP, IRC, and many more) are reserved for members only.

These restrictions are implemented with kernel blocks, so even if a non-member builds a personal copy of, say, an IRC client, it won't run on Grex.

Can I pay my dues with my credit card?

Yes! Memberships can be purchased through Paypal. Of course, you can still just mail in a check if you prefer.

Does it cost Grex money if I pay by credit card?

Yes, a bit. Paypal charges us a fee to receive money you send us - go to www.paypal.com and click on "fees" at the bottom of the page to see how much. At the time of this writing, it's $.30 plus 2.2% for most payments.

We're willing to pay that fee, but if it bothers you that Grex gets less money this way than we would if you sent a check, you are of course welcome to increase your payment slightly to cover the fee. We would be most grateful.

Our bank doesn't charge us any fee to deposit checks, money orders, or cash.

Is there a form I need to fill out to become a member?

No. To become a member, just send in your payment, along with your login name and ID (if necessary), and that's all there is to it. We try to keep things as form-free as possible, though you may need to give us a bit more information if you are paying by credit card.

Are my membership dues tax-deductible?

Yes. Cyberspace Communications is a 501(c)3 corporation, so donations to it are tax-deductible. Since the only benefits received in return for membership dues are frequently-exercisable rights, membership dues are donations and therefore deductible in full.

If I become a member, can I run an IRC bot such as Eggdrop on Grex?

Yes, if you so choose, but please do not overwhelm our system!

If I become a member, can I put pictures on my web site?

Users are not allowed to store images on Grex, whether they are members or not. (This is because Grex's bandwidth is so limited.) However you can store an image somewhere else and have it display on your Grex web page. For instance, your page could include a line like this:

<img src=http://www.somedomain.com/mypic.jpg>

As long as the images are stored off of Grex, they don't go through our link when a user goes to your page. So a reference like the one above is just fine.

Do I have to identify myself in order to become a member of Grex?

Yes. Although you are welcome to use Grex anonymously, or donate money anonymously, you must send some ID to the treasurer in order to become a member.

Why?

There are two reasons Grex requires ID from its members:

While we are very comfortable allowing anonymous users access to Grex, we are not comfortable unleashing them on the rest of the Internet. It would be irresponsible of the Grex administration to allow people we can't identify to SSH through Grex to other systems, so we require ID from everyone we allow to do that.
Cyberspace Communications is required by the State of Michigan to maintain an up-to-date list of members. Implied in this requirement is that we make sure no two memberships are held by the same person. So we require ID to connect accounts with real people and make sure no one has the ability to vote twice in Grex elections.

What forms of ID are acceptable?

First of all, if you pay with a personal check that has your name pre-printed on it, that's good enough right there. You don't need to include any extra ID. If you're a minor and your parent or guardian writes the check, we'll accept that as ID.

If you pay with cash or a money order, include a photocopy of a driver's license, passport, or other official ID. If you don't have a driver's license or passport, but do have something, send mail to the treasurer and ask if your ID is OK.

I'm paying for my membership with Paypal. Do I still need to send ID?

It depends. If you are a verified member of Paypal, then you don't need to send Grex ID. Otherwise, you do. Paypal verification is different depending on what country you're in; verified members in the US have confirmed their ownership of a bank account. For more information on Paypal verification Click here.

But the whole point of using Paypal was I didn't want to send mail! Is there any other way I can send the treasurer my ID?

Yes. There are three ways to submit ID:

Scan your ID and email the scan to treasurer@grex.org.
Show your ID to the treasurer in person. (This is probably not practical unless you live in Ann Arbor.)
Photocopy the ID and send the copy to:

Cyberspace Communications, Inc.
P.O. Box 4432
Ann Arbor, MI 48106-4432
USA

Who will get to see my ID?

All the information about members' names, addresses, and other ID data is available only to the treasurer and is not stored on the net. The list of the usernames of people who are members is in a publicly readable file, however. (So for instance, suppose someone named Dave White, whose Grex username is "waffles", becomes a member. Anyone at all can read the membership list and find that "waffles" is a member. However, if Mr. White so chooses, he needn't let anyone but the treasurer know the real name of the owner of account "waffles".)

Needless to say, we never sell mailing lists or anything like that.

Note: Most people who become members aren't at all worried about concealing their identity. So by default, the treasurer publicly thanks new members using both their real names and their usernames. If you're concerned about anonymity and don't want your real name used, be sure to tell the treasurer that when you first send in dues money.

I live outside the U.S. and don't have access to a U.S. dollar checking account. Can I become a member?

If you have a MasterCard or Visa, you may be able to pay for your membership using Paypal. Otherwise this can be a real problem. We're sorry we can't accept payment in any currency other than U.S. dollars.

Here are a few things which have worked for people in the past. Note all of these methods require that you submit ID.

Find a bank that does business in the U.S. and ask for a draft in U.S. dollars. Citibank and First of America are examples of U.S. Banks.
Request a draft in dollars from the Bank of India.
Have a friend in the U.S. send us money, and reimburse him or her through other channels. For instance, we had one user who was an Indian living in the U.S., and he said he'd pay Grex money if people in India would give money to his sister.
Use an international money order. Unfortunately we've heard this is expensive.
Send a MoneyGram. This is also expensive, but it works.
Send Cash money. We don't recommend this, of course, because there's absolutely nothing anyone can do about it if it doesn't make it here safely. But people have used this method successfully.

If you have any other ideas we can add to this list, send mail to the treasurer.

Can my organization become a member of Grex?

Yes. Institutions may become members of Grex. They have the same privileges as individual members, with the exception that they may not vote in Grex elections or serve on the Grex Board of Directors. This is to keep any one person from obtaining more than one vote in any election.

It should be noted that while incidental use of Grex for commercial purposes is OK, Grex is not an appropriate platform for serious business ventures. A few of the reasons why are:

Grex is run entirely by volunteers. They do a fine job of maintaining the system, but they can't be counted on to jump when you say jump (or to move at "the speed of business.")
Grex's budget is tiny compared to all but the smallest of commercial ventures. A business that's doing any volume at all would do well to invest in a commercial ISP account.
Grex memberships are not contracts for services, they are donations. Since Grex is run democratically, the benefits of membership are decided by the members. So far in Grex's history the membership has been very conservative about changing Grex policy on things like membership benefits, and it's likely that will continue to be so. But you should be aware of the possibility that it might not always be so.

That said, if you just want to use Grex occasionally to sell a few things, it's OK. And we would, of course, appreciate your support.

What kind of ID is needed for an institutional membership?

Institutions that become members need to designate a contact person who is responsible for use of the account. The contact person needs to submit his or her ID, which must meet the same criteria as the ID of individual members. (See What forms of ID are acceptable. Personal checks count as ID, but corporate checks do not.) The institution is responsible for making sure the contact person and his or her ID stay up to date. In other words, let us know if the contact person changes.

How soon after I send in my payment will I be made a member?

Grex's mail goes to a P.O. box, and then the treasurer picks it up. So add a few days to the time it takes for a letter to get from where you are to Ann Arbor in order to estimate the delay.

Once the treasurer receives your mail, you should be added to the membership rolls as soon as possible.

If you pay using Paypal, you'll be added as soon as you send in ID. Note: a VERIFIED PayPal account (the definition of which varies by country) can constitute valid ID. See the Member page for why you either need to verify your PayPal account or send valid ID.

Is there anything that might prevent me from being added right away?

Your membership might be delayed if:

You pay by Paypal, money order or with cash and forget to include a photocopy of some form of ID.
You forget to include your Grex username somewhere in your letter. (Writing it on the check or sending email to the treasurer work nicely.)

How will I know when my membership is activated?

You should get email from the treasurer when you are added to the membership rolls.

Can I donate old computer equipment in lieu of paying dues?

No thank you. We are no longer looking for old computer equipment. As hardware has decreased in cost and increased in power, and open source software has matured, we find that we no longer have to be bottom feeders in the way we once were.

Further, it is longstanding Grex policy that you can't pay for a membership with equipment, only money. Sorry! We have made only one or two exceptions to this over the history of Grex. The main purpose of membership dues is to provide cash to pay the regular expenses (such as phone bills and co-location costs) that operating Grex incurs. We've decided, therefore, to stay away from accepting alternative payments for memberships.

I am an experienced UNIX user. Can I do system administration work in lieu of paying dues?

We are always delighted to have new volunteers. One of the things that Grex needs most urgently is more people to answer "help" requests. We recommend you check out the helpers conference. Also you should read the Grex Staff Notes.

However, as with donations of hardware, volunteering for the staff cannot be used to pay for membership. (Even longtime staff people have to pay dues to be members.) Again, membership dues generate the money we need to pay the bills to keep Grex running, so we stay away from giving out memberships to anyone who doesn't pay.

What can I do if I don't like these policies?

Grex is a democratic institution, and all its policies are ultimately decided by the membership. If you think a policy should be changed, enter an item in the coop conference suggesting the change. If enough people agree with you, you'll get what you want. (And if they don't, you'll find out why.)

$Id: memfaq.xhtml 1442 2014-03-23 17:39:07Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.

Free Grex Shell Accounts

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

(Note: Grex does not allow bots of ANY kind)

Anyone can obtain a free shell account on Grex. There are many shells available to choose from. To get an account, just use ssh to connect to grex.org and log in as newuser. If you cannot get connected, see Grex's SSH information page. An alternative way to create your account is to select the "Get A Free Account" link, either here, or on the main page. You will still need to be able to SSH in order to use it. Either way, you will need to fill out a form which takes a few minutes, and then wait a few minutes while the account is created on-line. It will be ready for use without further delay, but will be relatively useless until it has been validated.

Grex is a popular site, and can become overloaded some times during the day. Please do not log on more than one session at a time.

There are important limitations to Grex accounts, which you should note before you get your account.

Outgoing internet access is blocked for free accounts. So you won't be able to use ssh or FTP. Certain ports remain unblocked, so that you can access the web via lynx or use finger, talk, or whois. You cannot overcome these blocks by replacing client programs.
You may feel free to use Grex's software development tools, but do not bring a copy of a program to Grex from an internet archive without checking with the Grex Staff (help@grex.org) first.
Some diagnostic programs have been abused and are available on a limited basis - these include ping, nmap and traceroute.
Programs will not run on Grex after you have logged out - they will be killed automatically. Daemon programs are not allowed and will be killed.
Abandoned accounts are deleted after three months without a log in. It does not matter whether you have a web page or whether you are using your account to forward mail. Regardless, you must log in so that we know that you are still using your account. Using Backtalk is treated the same as logging in.
You have 100 megabytes of disk storage. This is enforced by the honor system, so please cooperate.
Do not use your account to harass or attack others. Sending unwanted mail and attempting to break into another person's account are not acceptable, and will not be tolerated.

$Id: shell.xhtml 1418 2014-03-23 00:48:18Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.